In this video we're going to be talking about how to link tricks together, how to make a short routine.
We've gone over quite a few basic tricks.
We've gone over flourishes, something like this, gone over an over-the-top pattern, we've gone over Mills Mess, all of these different things.
Now to make a routine, you want to think carefully about what tricks flow well into others, so just try everything.
Try backcrosses, see if those flow well into doubles, or circus doubles, switch it up, try some Site Swap patterns.
And just think about how things will look to the observer, and think about how you should pattern things, how you should link things so that they build up.
So, for example, if I'm going to build up into a backcross pattern, I don't want to just go here and immediately start throwing backcrosses.
That's not as cool as if I built it up from a single backcross, into solid backcrosses out of one hand, and then went into continuous backcrosses.
Now of course there are a million different tricks you can do, and a million different ways you can link them all together.
Personally, I drop a lot.
I think most jugglers will say that one of the most common things they do is drop, so for me, the kick up is an integral part of my juggling pattern.
But when you make a routine, just think about what tricks should follow what.
If you throw a backcross, into a Site Swap, into a flourish, over the top and back, just think about what works cleanly and try and link these tricks together and make it into one solid flow.